Scott J. Briggs, PhD

Mobile: 214 326-4135

Email: hopingforclearskies@gmail.com
LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/sjbriggs/

WHOIAM

I am a strong and high-performing manager and project manager with a successful track record of delivering results on time, improving process and product quality, and solving problems. I am a motivated and confident individual committed to delivering the best value to my customers. I am a team player skilled in building effective and productive relationships across teams and departments. I have a broad technical background with experience in data warehousing, business intelligence, analytics, data security, application and web development, telephony, and data center infrastructure. I am also experienced in managing projects with distributed teams.

WHAT I HAVE DONE

- Managing the planning, development, and delivery of a greenfield enterprise data warehousing, analytics, and application platform leveraging Oracle's high performance Exadata database appliance. Responsible for delivering projects with \$10 million in total budget from 2011–2014.
- Managed the planning, development, and delivery of data warehousing and business intelligence initiatives including acquisitions which supported the growth of an automobile loan portfolio from \$2 billion to \$26 billion over four years.
- Managed the delivery of predictive analytics for decision support and risk management for automobile loan originations and servicing which helped the organization achieve more than \$500 million in pre-tax profit in 2010.
- Created and managed an enterprise service delivery and assurance team which transitioned new products and services to end users which enabled T-Mobile HotSpot to grow from 20 thousand to 1 million customers over a two year period.

TOP EXPERIENCE AREAS

- Project Management
- Program Management
- Release Management
- Tools MS Project, Rally

- SDLC Methodologies Waterfall, Agile-SCRUM, KanBan
- Analytics, Statistical Modeling, Machine Learning
- Team Building and Leadership
- Risk Analysis and Mitigation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Management Consultant, Data Warehouse/Business Intelligence VHA/Novation, Irving, TX (2011–2014)

- Managing the planning, development, and delivery of a greenfield enterprise data warehousing and business intelligence platform leveraging Oracle's high performance Exadata database appliance. The objective is to support near real-time reporting and analytics to position Novation's supply chain management business for growth in a changing health care environment.
- The projects include the development and operationalization of an operational data store, data mart, ETL, data center infrastructure, and application development.
- All projects have been delivered under budget.
- Executed a data center move with no issues and minimal down time for customers.
- Performed program and project management, release management, and scrum masters roles.
- Employed Agile-SCRUM, KanBan, and waterfall methodologies where appropriate to deliver projects.
- Utilized MS Project and Rally as tools to plan, manage, and track project details.
- Created and implemented a change and release management process to ensure timely and repeatable delivery of high quality data to customers.
- Received the Western Region Consultant of the Quarter for Q4 2013 in recognition of superior customer delivery.

Senior Project Manager/Manager, Data Warehouse/Business Intelligence Santander Consumer USA, Dallas, TX (2007–2011)

- Managed the planning, development, and delivery of data warehousing and business intelligence initiatives including acquisitions which supported the growth of an automobile loan portfolio from \$2 billion to \$26 billion over four years.
- Managed the delivery of predictive analytics for decision support and risk management for automobile loan financing and servicing.
- Managed a team of 4 business analysts in defining, testing, and implementing business requirements, technical specifications, and data analyses.
- Utilized Agile-SCRUM, KanBan, and waterfall methodologies where appropriate to deliver projects.
- Employed MS Project and Rally as tools to plan, manage, and track project details.

Manager, Project/Program/Release Management T-Mobile USA, Frisco, TX (2005-2007)

Managed a team of 8 project managers responsible for planning, development, and delivery of projects for change
management, application development, web portal and intranet, mobile devices, WiFi networking, data warehousing, and billing and financial reporting.

Senior Program Manager T-Mobile USA, Frisco, TX (2004–2005)

- Create and managed an enterprise service delivery and assurance team which transitioned new products and services to end users. Negotiated service-level agreements to ensure customer satisfaction across the lifetime of the products and services which enabled T-Mobile HotSpot to grow from 20 thousand to 1 million customers over a $2\frac{1}{2}$ year period. During this time, T-Mobile consistently earned the highest ranking in customer satisfaction from J. D. Power and Associates.
- Managed the development and delivery of a data warehouse to support reporting for marketing, product management, and sales.
- Managed several initiatives to design, implement, and deliver web content and application updates to the T-Mobile HotSpot web site.

Project Management Consultant *Verizon*, Irving, TX (2003–2004)

• Managed the development and delivery of an initiative to consolidate billing and ordering systems to support the rollout of FIOS Internet services across the United States.

Manager Software Development Alcatel, Plano, TX (2000–2002)

Managed a team of 30 software engineers located in one on-shore and two off-shore development centers which
developed and delivered a telecommunications switching platform.

Senior Project Manager DSC Communications, Plano, TX (1997–2000)

- Managed the development, testing, and integration of embedded software for a new broadband switching product. **Computer Systems Engineer** *Raytheon*, Garland, TX (1990–1997)
- Developed computer hardware, firmware, and software for signal processing applications for various customers in the defense and intelligence communities.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Ph.D, Public Policy and Political Economy, University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX

Dissertation: Health Information Technology: Assessing the Impact of Electronic Medical Records in Primary Care M.B.A., General Business, Amberton University, Dallas TX

B.S., Electrical Engineering, Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO

Data Science Specialization, Johns Hopkins University through Coursera (Expected Finish 2016)

Stanford Advanced Project Management (SCPM) Certification, Stanford University, Palo Alto, CA

Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification, Project Management Institute, 2003–2013